<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lodgings on Winter Tech Forum: A Self-Organizing Open Spaces Conference in Crested Butte, Colorado</title>
    <link>https://www.wintertechforum.com/lodging/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lodgings on Winter Tech Forum: A Self-Organizing Open Spaces Conference in Crested Butte, Colorado</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.wintertechforum.com/lodging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Lodging</title>
      <link>https://www.wintertechforum.com/lodging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.wintertechforum.com/lodging/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most popular things to do for conferences is to rent houses
together. You can do this through the conference mailing list &amp;ndash; often
one person finds the house, and then others come and fill it up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can also find further (albeit outdated in some places) &lt;a href=&#34;http://mindview.net/Seminars/Locations/CrestedButte/CrestedButte.html&#34;&gt;details
about lodging and how to get to Crested
Butte&lt;/a&gt;,
but if you&amp;rsquo;re in a hurry you can just call the Crested Butte Chamber of
Commerce at (800) 545-4505 and they will help you make a reservation.
Remember to ask for a reservation &lt;em&gt;in the town of Crested Butte&lt;/em&gt;, and
not on the mountain, in order to be close to the conference location.
However, in the Summer there are always more rooms available on the
mountain than in town, and the bus is very convenient to get from the
mountain to town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re on a budget, try the hostel or ask the Chamber of Commerce
about camping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://travelcrestedbutte.com/&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s another site&lt;/a&gt; about travel,
lodging and the Crested Butte experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group Houses:&lt;/strong&gt; Make sure you add yourself to the newsgroup for the
conference. People often organize to rent an entire house for the
conference, which can be more useful and fun. Once you&amp;rsquo;re on the
newsgroup, feel free to make arrangements with other attendees to rent
houses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>